# Justin Israel

# Software/Pipeline Developer

Miramar, Wellington 6022 New Zealand

US: +1 760 565 3381 NZ: +64 027 556 2477

Email: justinisrael@gmail.com

http://justinfx.com https://github.com/justinfx http://www.imdb.com/name/nm1920992

# **OBJECTIVE**

As a versatile and experienced software developer in the Visual FX industry, with a background including film production, compositing, roto/paint, fx, and supervision, I have an affinity for learning new techniques and applications quickly. This broad and applicable knowledge enables me to rapidly solve a wide range of problem spaces, and makes me an asset to Software, Visual FX, and Post-Production teams. I strive to work with teams of people who love challenges, love to learn, and love to build exciting solutions.

# **SKILLS**

Languages: Python, Cython, Go, C++, MEL

Framework/API: Qt, PySide/PyQt, Boost, Maya/Nuke APIs, OpenImageIO, ZeroMQ, ImageMagick,

•••

Web: Django (py), Martini/Gin (go), Sencha Touch/ExtJS, PHP, JavaScript

Visual Effects: Maya, Nuke, Fusion, Shake, Syntheyes, PFTrack, Boujou, Adobe

Photoshop/Premiere, Apple Final Cut, Autodesk Flame/Inferno

#### **EXPERIENCE**

Weta Digital, Wellington, New Zealand - Production Engineer

JAN 2013 - PRESENT

- Pipeline development, services, and tooling
- Dev: Asset Management, In-House Render Pipeline, Review Pipeline, Scene Description
  Pipeline

South Park Studios, Los Angeles, CA - Sr. Pipeline Developer

NOV 2008 - JAN 2013

- Direct development and support for artist pipeline at the award-winning 18+ season Comedy Central cartoon studio
- Maya python/mel scripting and development
- Nuke/Shake development
- Qube! Render Queue development
- Python/PyQt applications for production and general pipeline
- Resources, assets, tracking, and review pipelines

# **Custom Film Effects, Burbank, CA** - Compositor

MARCH 2008 - NOV 2008

- Digital artist at boutique visual effects studio
- Compositing, Paint, Roto, tool development
- Films: Tropic Thunder, Swing Vote, Mama Mia, Bride Wars

Sony Pictures Imageworks, Culver City, CA - Sr. Production Service Technician

JAN 2006 - MARCH 2008

- Feature Films: The Watchmen, I Am Legend, Spider-man 3
- Disk Mgmt, Production Support, Image Processing, Vendor I/O, Render Farm Management,
  Data/Shot/Show Archival
- Python scripting, Pipeline support / development
- Training: Katana, Bonsai (internal compositor), Flame/Inferno, Houdini, Maya, Massive

# Stan Winston Digital, Van Nuys, CA - 2D Digital Artist

JAN 2005 - JULY 2005

- Feature Films: Eight Below, Fantastic Four
- Digital Paint, Rotoscoping, and Compositing
- Matte preparation, grain removal, wire removal, dust / scratch repair / plate preparation

# **EDUCATION**

California State University Long Beach, CA - B.A. Film / Electronic Arts

SEPT 2003 - DEC 2005

Film / Video related production track; Visual FX Courses

Directed 4 films; Visual FX Supervisor; Editor: 2x; Director of Photography: 2x

Palomar College, San Marcos, CA - General Education

2002 - MAY 2003

CSU San Marcos, San Marcos, CA - General Education

2001 - 2002

# **OTHER EXPERIENCE**

Visual FX Supervisor: Commander And Chief (2012), The Compass (2009)

Freelance compositing, Freelance Video Production

Animation Training (2000-2001) at Newtek-Certified Lightwave Training Center

Daniel's Cablevision (2000), Carlsbad, CA: Production / Post-Production Intern at city cable provider